Welcome to this course on ChatGPT
Prompt Engineering for Developers.
I'm thrilled to have with
me Isa Fulford to
teach this along with me. She
is a member of
the technical staff of
OpenAI and had built
the popular ChatGPT Retrieval
plugin and a large
part of her work
has been teaching people
how to use LLM
or Large Language Model
technology in products. She's also
contributed to the OpenAI Cookbook that
teaches people prompting.
So thrilled
to have you with me.
And I'm thrilled to be here
and share some prompting
best practices with you
all.
So, there's been a lot of
material on the internet
for prompting with articles
like 30 prompts everyone
has to know. A lot of that has
been focused on the
chatGPT web user interface, which
many people are using to
do specific and often one-off tasks.
But, I think
the power of LLMs, large language
models, as a
developer tool, that is
using API calls to LLMs to quickly build
software applications, I think
that is still very underappreciated.
In fact, my team at AI Fund,
which is a sister company to
DeepLearning.ai, has been working with
many startups on
applying these technologies
to many different
applications, and it's been
exciting to see what LLM APIs
can enable developers to very quickly
build. So, in this
course, we'll share with
you some of the
possibilities for what you
can do, as well as
best practices for how you
can do them.
There's a lot of material to cover. First,
you'll learn some prompting best
practices for software
development, then we'll cover some
common use cases, summarizing, inferring, transforming,
expanding, and
then you'll
build a chatbot
using an LLM. We hope that this
will spark your imagination about new
applications that you
can build.
So in the development of
large language models or LLMs,
there have been broadly
two types of LLMs, which I'm
going to refer to as
base LLMs and instruction-tuned LLMs.
So, base LLM
has been trained to predict
the next word based on
text training data, often trained
on a large amount
of data from the
internet and other sources
to figure out what's the next
most likely word to follow. So, for example,
if you were to prompt us once
upon a time there
was a unicorn, it may complete
this, that is it may predict the next
several words are that
live in a magical
forest with all unicorn
friends.
But if you were to prompt us with
what is the capital of France,
then based on what articles
on the internet might have, it's
quite possible that the
base LLM will complete
this with what is France's largest
city, what is France's population and
so on, because articles on
the internet could
quite plausibly be
lists of quiz questions about the
country of France.
In contrast, an instruction-tuned
LLM, which is where a lot of
momentum of LLM research and
practice has been going, an
instruction-tuned LLM has been trained to
follow instructions. So, if you
were to ask it what is
the capital of France, it's much more
likely to output something
like, the capital of
France is Paris. So the way
that instruction-tuned LLMs are typically
trained is you start
off with a base
LLM that's been trained on a
huge amount of text data and further train
it, further fine-tune it with inputs
and outputs that are instructions
and good attempts
to follow those
instructions, and then often further refine
using a technique called
RLHF, reinforcement learning
from human feedback, to
make the system better
able to be helpful and
follow instructions. Because instruction-tuned
LLMs have been trained
to be
helpful, honest, and harmless,
so for example, they are
less likely to output problematic
text such as toxic
outputs compared to base
LLM, a lot of
the practical usage scenarios have been shifting toward
instruction-tuned LLMs. Some of
the best practices you
find on the internet may be
more suited for a
base LLM, but for
most practical applications today, we would
recommend most people
instead focus on
instruction-tuned LLMs which
are easier to
use and also,
because of the work
of OpenAI and other LLM
companies becoming safer and more aligned.
So, this course will focus
on best practices for instruction-tuned
LLMs, which is what we recommend
you use for most
of your applications. Before
moving on, I just want to
acknowledge the team from OpenAI and
DeepLearning.ai that
had contributed to the
materials that Isa and
I will be presenting. I'm very grateful
to Andrew Mayne, Joe Palermo, Boris
Power, Ted Sanders, and
Lillian Weng from OpenAI that
were very involved with us brainstorming
materials, vetting the materials
to put together the
curriculum for this short
course, and I'm also grateful on
the DeepLearning side for
the work of Geoff
Lodwig, Eddy Shyu and Tommy
Nelson. So, when you use an
instruction-tuned LLM, think of giving
instructions to another person, say
someone that's smart but
doesn't know the specifics of your task.
So, when an LLM doesn't work, sometimes
it's because the instructions weren't clear enough.
For example,
if you were to say,
please write me something about
Alan Turing. Well, in addition to that, it
can be helpful to be
clear about whether you
want the text to focus on his scientific
work or his personal
life or his role
in history or something
else. And if you
specify what you want
the tone of
the text to be,
should it take on the tone like a
professional journalist would write. Or is
it more of a
casual note that you
dash off to a friend?
That helps the LLM generate
what you want. And of
course, if you picture
yourself asking, say, a
fresh college graduate
to carry out this task for
you, if you can even
specify what snippets of text, they
should read in advance
to write this text about
Alan Turing, then that
even better sets up
that fresh college grad
for success to carry
out this task for
you. So, in the
next video, you see examples of how to
be clear and specific,
which is an important principle
of prompting LLMs. And you
also learn from Isa
a second principle of
prompting that is giving
the LLM time to
think. So with that,
let's go on to the next video.